Here, we have a couple of things.
这里有几个函数和变量
First, we have a global variable called number which just points to
首先有一个叫做 number 的全局变量 它设为了数字 3
the number three and we also have a higher order function called myFunction.
还有一个更高阶的函数 叫做 number
Inside myFunction, we have a local variable
在 myFunction 中有一个局部变量
called otherNumber which just points to the number one,
叫做 otherNumber 设成了数字 1
as well as a function called logger.
还有一个函数 叫做 logger
And all loggers does is just log otherNumber right to the console.
loggers 的作用是将 otherNumber 输出到控制台中
At the very end, myFunction returns logger.
在最后 myFunction 返回 logger
Let's invoke myFunction and then store that result into a variable called result.
我们调用 myFunction 并将该结果存储到叫做 result 的变量中
So, as you can see, the return value of my function being
调用 myFunction 后返回的值
called is going to be stored in a variable called result.
将存储在变量 result 中
And now if we invoke it,
如果调用 result
we see that it outputs one to the console.
可以看到它向控制台中输出了 1
So, how is this possible?
为何会这样？
Well, because of closure,
因为闭包的原因
logger captures the otherNumber variable which is declared locally inside myFunction.
logger 捕获了在 myFunction 内局部声明的 otherNumber 变量
In other words, the nested logger function is still able to
换句话说 嵌套的 logger 函数
access the otherNumber variable in its parent function scope,
依然能够访问父函数作用域内的 otherNumber 变量
even after the parent function returned.
即使在父函数返回之后
Let's check out this one a little bit more closely.
我们再仔细研究下该函数
What I'm going to do is refresh the console and do everything I just did,
我将刷新控制台并执行刚刚执行的操作
but there with debugger in there.
但是在这里添加调试程序
And now if we invoke it again,
现在如果再次调用 result
we've now paused execution and we're on this line of code, line seven.
我们暂停了执行代码并位于第七行
But if you check out what's going on on the right side of the screen,
查看屏幕右侧内容
we see closure over here.
会在这里看到闭包
Let's open it up. Pretty interesting.
打开它 很有趣
We see the otherNumber variable which is
这里有个 otherNumber 变量
the variable that the logger function closed over.
它是 logger 函数闭包的变量
So, to recap, functions like logger maintain a reference to its parent function scope,
总结下 logger 等函数即使在父函数返回后
which is myFunction, even after the parent function has returned.
也可以引用其父函数的作用域 即 myFunction